# Summary

I am a User Experience Designer with over eighteen years in digital design. As a User Experience Designer, my in-depth understanding of the design process allows me to meet user goals while balancing aesthetics and technical constraints. I design comprehensive design systems leveraging my extensive background in web design and development.

# Professional Experience

KBS March 2015-present

#### **Associate Director, User Experience**

November 2016-present

- Designed a 3D cabinet configurator for Stanley Black & Decker. Created a design system, user flows, usability tests, and comprehensive prototypes
- Built a skills matrix for the UX team to help visualize strengths and gaps.
   Established a Sketch and InVision workflow to streamline work between the UX, Design, and Development departments
- Led a design discovery to redesign the PODS website. Delivered a UX audit, competitive research, personas, journey maps, and usability testing

#### Senior User Experience Designer

March 2015-November 2016

- I led the responsive redesign of BMWUSA.com. Built a modular design system, responsive grid, wireframes, user flows, and prototypes
- Redesigned the sign up flows for the My BMW website. Created wireframes, user flows, interaction and technical documentation, and prototypes
- Designed a learning site for digital marketers at Hershey. Conducted user and stakeholder interviews, designed content types, and wireframes

### New York University

October 2008-March 2015

#### **User Experience Specialist**

Digital Communications Group, Information Technology Services August 2014–March 2015

- Designed and developed a new responsive user interface for Sakai—an open source Learning Management System. Wrote new HTML 5 templates and a Sass based CSS framework. Incorporated the user experience and user interface improvements from. NYU Classes
- Redesigned and prototyped a new user interface for NYU's Email Direct—a bulk email communication tool for NYU administrators

#### **User Experience Designer**

Academic Technology Services, Information Technology Services October 2011-August 2014

- Redesigned and developed a new user interface for NYU Classes—their Learning Management System (LMS). The redesign was based on extensive usability testing and research
- Created a 'Mobile First' prototype for our redesign of <u>MediaCommons</u>—a digital network for professors and post-graduate students of film and media studies

### **UX/UI Skills**

- Design Systems, Style Guides, & Visual Design
- Sketching, Storyboarding, & Paper Prototyping
- Wireframing, Card Sorting, & High-fidelity Prototyping
- · Usability Testing, User Interviews, & Personas

### **Technical Skills**

- Sketch, Photoshop, Illustrator, InVision, Principle
- Markup (HTML) & Styling (CSS)
- · Sass, Javascript & jQuery, Grunt & Gulp
- · Git & SVN, PHP, MySQL, Drupal

#### **Interactive Designer and Developer**

Faculty Technology Services, Information Technology Services
October 2008–October 2011

- Designed and developed <u>MediaCommons—a digital</u> network for professors and post-graduate students—using Drupal
- Established a distinctive look and feel for the MediaCommons network and it's project sites
- Designed and developed two platforms for viewing the digital collections of NYU Libraries. Allowing patrons to view both image based collections scanned books and photographs—and stream audio and video collections

### Columbia University

August 2001-September 2008

#### Senior Web Designer and Developer

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures (a small 'digital agency' within Columbia University)

May 2005-September 2008

 Designed and developed educational course content and departmental websites for Columbia University and affiliated non-profits

#### Web Designer and Developer

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures August 2001–May 2005

- Worked with Columbia University faculty to design and develop interactive eseminars and courses
- Designed and developed interactive maps, audio slideshows, podcasts, and video production and post-production for streaming video and DVD

### Scholastic

January 2000-May 2001

#### Web Designer

e-Scholastic

- Designed educational, commercial, and promotional websites for Scholastic
- Designed daily site graphics, interactive quizzes, and educational activities

# **Teaching**

The New School, Fall 2004-Spring 2008

Adjunct faculty member, Media Studies

 Courses: Foundations of Media Design, Digital Video Effects, and Motion Graphics with After Effects

Columbia University, Summer 2005–Summer 2008

Instructor, High School Program

• Course: Digital Filmmaking: From Initial Concept to Final Edit

## Education

1999–2007 **Ph.D. Media & Communication**, European Graduate School, Saas-Fee, Switzerland

1998-2001 Certificate in Film Production, The New School, New York, NY

1995–1996 M.Phil. Medieval History, Trinity College, Dublin University, Ireland

1991-1994 B.A. History and Philosophy, University College Dublin, Ireland

### Additional Information

### Organizations

- Co-Founder: NYU UX Group & NYU Web Designers and Developers Group
- Co-Organizer: DrupalCamp NYC 9 & 10 NYC Drupal Users Group
- Member: IxDA NYC UXPA Gotham Sass Meetup NYC Drupal Users Group Agile Experience Design Meetup Type Directors Club

# Selected Presentations, Event Organization, and Trainings

#### **Presentations**

- Better Tools for a Better Process at KBS' Bits & Bites 23rd March, 2017
- Beyond Putting Lipstick on the Pig at EdUI 2014 30th September, 2014
- Sakai: Meet MORPHEUS at Open Apereo 2014 2nd June, 2014
- Rapid Prototyping Techniques at TorchTech: UX Networking Breakfast 23rd April, 2014
- Fixing Broken User Experience at NYU ITS All Hands Meeting 21st September, 2012
- MediaCommons 2.0 at Digital Library Federation Forum 5th May, 2009

### **Event Organization**

- UX Networking Breakfast Co-Organizer TorchTech & NYU UX group 23rd April, 2014
- UX @ NYU Co-Organizer NYU UX group 14th November, 2013
- Usability @ NYU Co-Organizer NYU UX group 11th December, 2012
- DrupalCamp NYC 9 & 10 Co-Organizer & Designer NYC Drupal Users Group June & December 2011

#### **Trainings**

- Design Teams Are a Design Exercise: How to Build, Inspire and Keep Design Teams (Happy) with Alberta Soranzo & Martina Hodges-Schell, Interaction 17 — February 2017
- Leading Creative Ideation with Christian Linsey & Jen Zhao, Cooper U May 2016
- Design Leadership with Teresa Brazen & Lane Halley, Cooper U August 2015
- Scaling User Interfaces with Amy Schade, Nielsen Norman Group August 2014
- UX Leadership with Kim Goodwin, Rosenfeld Media October 2012
- Do It Yourself Usability Testing with Steve Krug, Rosenfeld Media May 2012
- Sketching Interfaces with Jason Mesut & Sam Smith, Interaction 12 February 2012
- Mobile Prototyping Essentials with Rachel Hinman, Interaction 12 February 2012